Luke Cassady-Dorion

Luke@SPStories.com www.luke.gallery

profile

For the past 26 years, I've worked at the intersection of technology and art. I began my career writing Java in the 90s and 00s. During the Web2 era, I launched a YouTube channel that grew to 650K subscribers and received awards for its dedication to social causes. My professional journey includes roles in developer relations, software engineering, video editing, and film directing. I've written books in both English and Thai. I'm at home on camera and excel at helping others feel comfortable in front of an audience.

I'm fluent in English and Thai and speak Spanish at a B1 level.

experience

<u>Irys</u>, Developer Relations, November 2022 – October 2024

- Wrote <u>comprehensive documentation</u> detailing the use of our tools and protocol.
- Created <u>engaging videos for X and YouTube</u> to explain our protocol to a broad audience.
- Wrote <u>guides and tutorials</u> that educate developers through project-based learning.
- Created code repositories showcasing clear use cases for our products.
- Developed an <u>open-source UI library</u> to help developers kickstart their projects.
- Designed a gamified developer education experience, leading to over 40K <u>developers completing challenges and minting NFTs</u> as proof of their accomplishments.
- Established and grew our <u>YouTube channel</u> to 33K subscribers.
- Collaborated with business development and marketing teams to enhance developer outreach.
- Worked 1:1 to support our developers.

A Single Production Company, Co-Founder, 2010 – 2020

- Directed the award-winning feature-length documentary film "<u>The Cheer Ambassadors</u>".
- Managed a full-time staff of 5 and teams of 20+ contractors on shoots.

AbsoluteYou, Senior Yoga and Pilates Instructor, 2004 – 2023

- Helped grow a boutique fitness studio from 3 to 10 studios and grew our teaching staff from 10 to 100.
- Launched a new social media team that led to 200% growth in Instagram and Facebook subscribers.

Medem, Co-Founder, CTO, 1999 – 2003

- Built a HIPAA-compliant secure messaging system connecting physicians and patients.
- Managed a team of 10+ developers.

Metis LLC / Healtheon / WebMD, Senior Software Engineer, 1997 – 1998

- Designed and built a data integration system to merge backend data reporting systems.
- Created a cross-platform Java client that displayed and analyzed data from multiple sources.

publications

- Yogi Boy: How I Learned To Breathe 2011
 Author (Thai language book)
- Java Distributed Objects 1998
 Co-author and primary editor
- Industrial Strength Java 1997
 Co-author and primary editor

education

Ramkhamhaeng University, BA Thai Language Studies, 2007-2012

As a personal project, I returned to university to study Thai literature and language origins. After 4.5 years, I became the only Westerner to ever graduate from the university's strenuous program.

Drexel University, Computer Science, 1995-1997

After two years, I dropped out to move to San Francisco and help start a healthcare technology company.